<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minisforum on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/minisforum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Minisforum on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/minisforum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VCF9 - Full-blown VCF 9 on 2 MS-A2 PCs</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-ms-a2-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-ms-a2-special/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past, I built all my labs in a nested structure, which worked well, but now the demands on me and my lab are increasing because I want more.&#xA;I want to try more, even in areas I previously neglected. The idea of a redesign took shape in my head, and I knew there had to be more possibilities with my hardware.&#xA;Above all, I wanted to work with VCF Automation, because it is essential for multi-tenancy environments and replaces vCloud Director.&#xA;And let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, automation is a resource hog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Lab – Lab setup</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/tales-from-the-lab-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/tales-from-the-lab-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot about the actual lab setup in the past, but it was always about the hardware and not how I manage my labs or, more recently, how I have built up my vcf fleet.&#xA;I want to change that here now, as I have received an increasing number of requests for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s jump right in. First things first, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the physical lab infrastructure. That&amp;rsquo;s my basis for everything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab V6 - It’s not just Taylor Swift who has different eras, my home lab does too</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an exciting few weeks. I was part of the VCF9 beta and ran several VCF instances in parallel, which meant I kept running into performance bottlenecks.&#xA;On top of that, the Minisforum A2 was finally available. But first things first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;25-gbs-lan---and-what-i-have-learned&#34;&gt;2.5 Gb/s LAN - and what I have learned&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, where should I start? I bought the Mikrotik CRS326-4C+20G+2Q for my NUCs, which offered me 20x 2.5 GB/s ports and wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly cheap at around 800 euros.&#xA;In hindsight, I can say that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a good investment. Not that the switch is bad, it&amp;rsquo;s not, but as of today, I only use exactly 2 2.5G ports.&#xA;For this purpose, I utilize all 10G and 40G ports (with brakeout) as 10G ports are now in short supply. Following the recent upgrade, I have exactly one 10G port remaining in the entire lab.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m actually considering selling the Switch again.&#xA;But hey, that&amp;rsquo;s part of homelabbing. Sometimes you just make bad investments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Lab - Minisforum MS-A2</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ms-a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:14:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ms-a2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being impressed with the performance and form factor of the Minisforum &lt;strong&gt;MS-01&lt;/strong&gt;, I had to get my hands on their latest beast: the &lt;strong&gt;MS-A2&lt;/strong&gt;, powered by AMD&amp;rsquo;s latest Zen 5 architecture.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s also exciting to test a gadget before &lt;a href=&#34;https://williamlam.com/&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for letting me be the first (I&amp;rsquo;m just kidding, of course).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll give you a quick rundown of both systems and how they compare—especially from a homelab perspective focused on virtualization, low noise, and energy-efficient high performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
