<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vcf on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/vcf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vcf on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:14:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/vcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Lab - Minisforum MS-A2</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ms-a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:14:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ms-a2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being impressed with the performance and form factor of the Minisforum &lt;strong&gt;MS-01&lt;/strong&gt;, I had to get my hands on their latest beast: the &lt;strong&gt;MS-A2&lt;/strong&gt;, powered by AMD&amp;rsquo;s latest Zen 5 architecture.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s also exciting to test a gadget before &lt;a href=&#34;https://williamlam.com/&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for letting me be the first (I&amp;rsquo;m just kidding, of course).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll give you a quick rundown of both systems and how they compare—especially from a homelab perspective focused on virtualization, low noise, and energy-efficient high performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReSTNSX with HCX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/restnsx-with-hcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:00:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/restnsx-with-hcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have already written about my experiences with HCX in the past and as brilliant as the tool is for the migration of different workloads, the rework with the distributed firewall can be painful. Because what HCX can&amp;rsquo;t do is move firewall rules or security objects. Fortunately, there is a solution for this: ReSTNSX.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is ReSTNSX? ReSTNSX describes itself as follows: The ReSTNSX platform simplifies consumption of VMware&amp;rsquo;s NSX API to increase visibility and reduce the risk of errors. Our mission is to enable administrators to easily configure and operate NSX with a straightforward and intuitive user experience.&#xA;We will see in this post whether it is really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF - How to use the Broadcom Download Token</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-token/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Broadcom is currently changing the access to their public repo. This affects many products. Affected are vCenter, ESXi Updates, vSAN File Services and of course VCF.&#xA;The changes are far-reaching. The repo URL has changed and also the way it can be accessed. With the username and password of the Broadcom account, access will no longer work from April 23, 2025. Time to take a look at the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Quick Tip - WLD with single NSX Manager</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-single-nsx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:42:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-single-nsx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick VCF tip for anyone who wants to deploy VCF but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have endless resources in the lab. With a few minor adjustments, it is possible to deploy a VI Workload WLD or even the Management WLD with just one NSX manager.&#xA;We can also reduce the MGMT domain to three hosts. The only more economical way is through the convert and NFS. In this case, a management domain with two hosts is possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Stretched Cluster</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-stretched-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-stretched-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is my third article in my VCF Homelab series.&#xA;On second thought, I may have put the cart before the horse, because a stretched vSAN cluster requires a functioning management domain.&#xA;But ok, that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother us now. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cover all the essentials of the deployment in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-benefits-of-a-stretched-vsan-cluster-and-why-does-it-have-to-be-vsan&#34;&gt;What are the benefits of a stretched vSAN cluster and why does it have to be vSAN?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, first the obvious.&#xA;We have to use vSAN because we have a consolidated design here and VCF (version 5.2.1) does not allow any other principal storage in the consolidated design (also, this article is about a vSAN stretched cluster).&#xA;Secondly, we want to use the synchronous replication of vSAN to the second site. Another reason is “German Angst”. We want to have redundancy here and a muti AZ design. In Germany, there have traditionally been stretched clusters across multiple fire compartments or buildings for a long time. In the past, I myself have already implemented such scenarios with layer 2 over layer 3 (aka VxLAN).&#xA;The much more elegant way (and also the way supported by VCF) is the vSAN stretched cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Import Tool - Enable Overlay in an imported VCF Domain</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-overlay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My blog is a follow-up to my article &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;VCF Import Tool - Run VCF with NFS as principal Storage&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and covers the activation of the overlay network after I have successfully converted an ESXi cluster to a VCF management domain using the VCF Import Tool.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The VCF import tool still has a few limitations. Among other things, no NSX TEP interface is configured in VCF 5.2.1 after the convert or import. Without the tunnel endpoints it is not possible to use NSX overlay networks. In this blog I will show which steps you have to take to prepare NSX so that we can create and use overlay networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Import Tool - Run VCF with NFS as principal Storage </title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VCF is a powerful platform designed to simplify the deployment of vSphere, NSX and the Aria product family.&#xA;This is both a blessing and a curse. On the one hand, the Cloudbuilder and SDDC Manager significantly simplify deployment, but this also takes away a certain amount of flexibility.&#xA;In addition, not every customer starts on a greenfield site.&#xA;Another point is the need for resources, which affects us home labbers in particular.&#xA;Many want to prepare for the new VCP exams and are now forced to deploy VCF in their Homelab.&#xA;There are already many solutions for this, such as the Holodeck, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lamw/vcf-automated-lab-deployment&#34;&gt;Automated Lab Deployment Scrip&lt;/a&gt;) or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lamw/vcf-automated-import-lab-deployment&#34;&gt;Automated VMware Cloud Foundation Import Lab Deployment&lt;/a&gt; script (both from the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://williamlam.com/&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;), but in my view this is too far removed from the kind of deployment that a customer will experience.&#xA;Therefore I will show several ways how to create VCF as close as possible to a real deployment without needing the real resources.&#xA;In this article I would like to show you how to do a convert with the VCF Import Tool. I will write more articles about VCF deployment in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migration with HCX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/migration-with-hcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/migration-with-hcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was brought in to help with a customer project that involved a VCF setup and migrating the workload domains to a new VCF deployment. The challenge of this project was that we had to adopt the existing networks without making any changes while also reducing the downtime of the workloads to an absolute minimum. We used HCX and network extension to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hcx&#34;&gt;What is HCX?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VMware HCX is an application mobility platform designed to simplify application migration, workload redeployment, and disaster recovery in data centers and clouds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab V5</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 02:00:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-homelab-journey-from-unraid-beginnings-to-version-5&#34;&gt;My Homelab Journey: From Unraid Beginnings to Version 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building and optimizing a homelab has always been a passion of mine. Since its inception, my homelab has gone through several iterations, constantly evolving to meet my goals of achieving maximum performance while minimizing power consumption, noise, and physical space requirements. Here is a snapshot of my journey, culminating in the current Version 5 of my homelab.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginning-unraid-with-custom-hardware&#34;&gt;The Beginning: Unraid with Custom Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My homelab journey began with a custom-built Unraid server featuring an Intel i3 11th Generation processor and 64 GB of RAM. This setup acted as an all-in-one solution for storage, virtualization, and container workloads. I even conducted simple nested vSphere tests on this server during its early days. Today, the server is still in use as a storage and Docker host, although I have replaced the underlying hardware four times to keep up with evolving requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAC Learning is your friend</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/mac-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:54:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/mac-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When working with nested ESXi environments, understanding the interplay between MAC Learning, Promiscuous Mode, and Forged Transmits is critical. These settings significantly affect how traffic flows in virtualized networks, especially in scenarios involving virtualized hypervisors or advanced network configurations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MAC Learning: Think of it as a switch-like behavior in your virtual environment. It optimizes network traffic by ensuring that each virtual machine (VM) receives only the packets meant for its MAC address.&#xA;Without MAC learning, when the ESXi VM&amp;rsquo;s vNIC connects to a switch port, it only contains a static MAC address.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-vSphere/8.0/vsphere-networking/GUID-E0246B3D-9FB1-4976-8217-5C085863EA9A.html&#34;&gt;(more Information about MAC learning)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
