<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:10:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VCF 9 - NSX VPC Part 3 - Security</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:10:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc-part3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my two other VPC articles, I showed you the basics and the differences between &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc/&#34;&gt;centralized deployment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc-part2/&#34;&gt;distributed deployment&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Today, I would like to write something about security, as VPCs offer various possibilities in this area.&#xA;VPCs provide a certain degree of isolation through their private networks, as these cannot be easily routed from outside the VPC.&#xA;But what if we want to protect a VM from the public network or a private VM that has been assigned a public IP? This is where the distributed firewall and gateway firewall come into play.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s find out exactly how.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF 9 - Migration to central VCF Operations instance</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-operations-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-operations-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where should I start? Perhaps I should describe my starting point.&#xA;I deployed a nested lab with VCF9 for the VCF9 beta, so far so good.&#xA;This lab came with its own VCF Operations. Now we are GA and I am lucky enough to have 256 core VCF9 licenses.&#xA;I wanted to upgrade part of my hardware lab to ESX9 because I also want to test memory tiering in its final version, and that&amp;rsquo;s where my problems start.&#xA;In VCF9, there are no more keys and you have to license your products via VCF Operations and vCenter.&#xA;This also applies to VVF, or if you want to use ESX9 on your physical lab hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF 9 - NSX VPC Part 2 - distributed Transit Gateway</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the second article in a series of articles (number of articles unknown) about VPCs in VCF 9.&#xA;If you are not familiar with VPCs and have not yet come across this topic, I recommend reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc/&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; first.&#xA;I will not go into all the basics again in this article, as these were already explained in the first article.&#xA;In this article, I will look at the distributed deployment of VPCs and show how VPCs can also be used without an edge cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSX - IDFW &amp; DFW Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-dfw-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-dfw-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to keep it brief and share a quick tip for all Identity (distributed) firewall administrators.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone has been in this situation: you&amp;rsquo;ve written a nice new Identity firewall, but for some reason it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&#xA;If it were a normal firewall rule in NSX, I would first check the Traceflow Tool, but unfortunately that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with the Identity firewall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-identity-firewall&#34;&gt;What is the Identity Firewall?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An identity firewall does not make firewall decisions based on IP addresses, but uses user and group information to apply security policies.&#xA;It identifies users based on their login credentials and dynamically assigns them appropriate access rights and firewall rules.&#xA;This enables more granular control and improved protection, as access permissions are directly linked to the actual identity of the user.&#xA;If you want to know how I used this for one of my customers, you can read about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-idfw-vdi/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab V6 - It’s not just Taylor Swift who has different eras, my home lab does too</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an exciting few weeks. I was part of the VCF9 beta and ran several VCF instances in parallel, which meant I kept running into performance bottlenecks.&#xA;On top of that, the Minisforum A2 was finally available. But first things first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;25-gbs-lan---and-what-i-have-learned&#34;&gt;2.5 Gb/s LAN - and what I have learned&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, where should I start? I bought the Mikrotik CRS326-4C+20G+2Q for my NUCs, which offered me 20x 2.5 GB/s ports and wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly cheap at around 800 euros.&#xA;In hindsight, I can say that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a good investment. Not that the switch is bad, it&amp;rsquo;s not, but as of today, I only use exactly 2 2.5G ports.&#xA;For this purpose, I utilize all 10G and 40G ports (with brakeout) as 10G ports are now in short supply. Following the recent upgrade, I have exactly one 10G port remaining in the entire lab.&#xA;That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m actually considering selling the Switch again.&#xA;But hey, that&amp;rsquo;s part of homelabbing. Sometimes you just make bad investments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF 9 - NSX VPC Part 1 - centralized Transit Gateway</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf9-nsx-vpc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where to start? The VPC feature has been available in NSX for a long time, but it has often been somewhat under the radar. In VCF 9, VPC is now more than present and small spoiler - I say rightly so!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But wait, from the top, what are VPCs anyway?&#xA;VMware says NSX Virtual Private Clouds is an abstraction layer that enables the creation of standalone virtual private cloud networks within an NSX project in order to use network and security services in a self-service usage model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Lab - Minisforum MS-A2</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ms-a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:14:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ms-a2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being impressed with the performance and form factor of the Minisforum &lt;strong&gt;MS-01&lt;/strong&gt;, I had to get my hands on their latest beast: the &lt;strong&gt;MS-A2&lt;/strong&gt;, powered by AMD&amp;rsquo;s latest Zen 5 architecture.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s also exciting to test a gadget before &lt;a href=&#34;https://williamlam.com/&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for letting me be the first (I&amp;rsquo;m just kidding, of course).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll give you a quick rundown of both systems and how they compare—especially from a homelab perspective focused on virtualization, low noise, and energy-efficient high performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReSTNSX with HCX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/restnsx-with-hcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:00:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/restnsx-with-hcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have already written about my experiences with HCX in the past and as brilliant as the tool is for the migration of different workloads, the rework with the distributed firewall can be painful. Because what HCX can&amp;rsquo;t do is move firewall rules or security objects. Fortunately, there is a solution for this: ReSTNSX.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is ReSTNSX? ReSTNSX describes itself as follows: The ReSTNSX platform simplifies consumption of VMware&amp;rsquo;s NSX API to increase visibility and reduce the risk of errors. Our mission is to enable administrators to easily configure and operate NSX with a straightforward and intuitive user experience.&#xA;We will see in this post whether it is really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSX Expiring Transport Node Certificates</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-expiring-tn-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-expiring-tn-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In NSX versions &lt;strong&gt;4.1.x&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;4.2.0&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;edge transport nodes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;host transport nodes&lt;/strong&gt; are instantiated using certificates with a &lt;strong&gt;validity period of only 825 days&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;This is obviously not desirable behavior and has been fixed in newer versions of NSX. Interestingly, I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen anything about this in the changelog.&#xA;In NSX versions 3.X and 4.2.1 and higher, these certificates are valid for 10 years. But what exactly does that mean?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VMUG Connect St. Louis 2025</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vmug-connect-stl-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:00:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vmug-connect-stl-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vmug-st-louis--between-tech-talks-and-travel-vibes&#34;&gt;VMUG St. Louis – Between Tech Talks and Travel Vibes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, I had the chance to combine two things I really enjoy – community and travel. Together with two colleagues from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evoila.de&#34;&gt;evoila&lt;/a&gt;, I made my way to the VMUG Connect in St. Louis. While the trip started as a tech-focused event, it turned into much more than just work. Exploring a new city, meeting passionate people from the community, and exchanging ideas over a coffee (or two) made this a truly special experience. And when I write coffee, I usually mean beer. I guess I&amp;rsquo;m German after all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF - How to use the Broadcom Download Token</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-token/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Broadcom is currently changing the access to their public repo. This affects many products. Affected are vCenter, ESXi Updates, vSAN File Services and of course VCF.&#xA;The changes are far-reaching. The repo URL has changed and also the way it can be accessed. With the username and password of the Broadcom account, access will no longer work from April 23, 2025. Time to take a look at the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Quick Tip - WLD with single NSX Manager</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-single-nsx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:42:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-single-nsx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick VCF tip for anyone who wants to deploy VCF but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have endless resources in the lab. With a few minor adjustments, it is possible to deploy a VI Workload WLD or even the Management WLD with just one NSX manager.&#xA;We can also reduce the MGMT domain to three hosts. The only more economical way is through the convert and NFS. In this case, a management domain with two hosts is possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Stretched Cluster</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-stretched-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-stretched-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is my third article in my VCF Homelab series.&#xA;On second thought, I may have put the cart before the horse, because a stretched vSAN cluster requires a functioning management domain.&#xA;But ok, that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother us now. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cover all the essentials of the deployment in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-benefits-of-a-stretched-vsan-cluster-and-why-does-it-have-to-be-vsan&#34;&gt;What are the benefits of a stretched vSAN cluster and why does it have to be vSAN?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, first the obvious.&#xA;We have to use vSAN because we have a consolidated design here and VCF (version 5.2.1) does not allow any other principal storage in the consolidated design (also, this article is about a vSAN stretched cluster).&#xA;Secondly, we want to use the synchronous replication of vSAN to the second site. Another reason is “German Angst”. We want to have redundancy here and a muti AZ design. In Germany, there have traditionally been stretched clusters across multiple fire compartments or buildings for a long time. In the past, I myself have already implemented such scenarios with layer 2 over layer 3 (aka VxLAN).&#xA;The much more elegant way (and also the way supported by VCF) is the vSAN stretched cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Import Tool - Enable Overlay in an imported VCF Domain</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-overlay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My blog is a follow-up to my article &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;VCF Import Tool - Run VCF with NFS as principal Storage&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and covers the activation of the overlay network after I have successfully converted an ESXi cluster to a VCF management domain using the VCF Import Tool.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The VCF import tool still has a few limitations. Among other things, no NSX TEP interface is configured in VCF 5.2.1 after the convert or import. Without the tunnel endpoints it is not possible to use NSX overlay networks. In this blog I will show which steps you have to take to prepare NSX so that we can create and use overlay networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VCF Import Tool - Run VCF with NFS as principal Storage </title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VCF is a powerful platform designed to simplify the deployment of vSphere, NSX and the Aria product family.&#xA;This is both a blessing and a curse. On the one hand, the Cloudbuilder and SDDC Manager significantly simplify deployment, but this also takes away a certain amount of flexibility.&#xA;In addition, not every customer starts on a greenfield site.&#xA;Another point is the need for resources, which affects us home labbers in particular.&#xA;Many want to prepare for the new VCP exams and are now forced to deploy VCF in their Homelab.&#xA;There are already many solutions for this, such as the Holodeck, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lamw/vcf-automated-lab-deployment&#34;&gt;Automated Lab Deployment Scrip&lt;/a&gt;) or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lamw/vcf-automated-import-lab-deployment&#34;&gt;Automated VMware Cloud Foundation Import Lab Deployment&lt;/a&gt; script (both from the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://williamlam.com/&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;), but in my view this is too far removed from the kind of deployment that a customer will experience.&#xA;Therefore I will show several ways how to create VCF as close as possible to a real deployment without needing the real resources.&#xA;In this article I would like to show you how to do a convert with the VCF Import Tool. I will write more articles about VCF deployment in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetKVM - all show and no substance?</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/jetkvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/jetkvm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jetkvm-a-kickstarter-project&#34;&gt;JetKVM a Kickstarter Project&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, there we have another kickstarter project. JetKVM advertises itself as a cheap, fast and open-source network KVM solution. It should provide 60FPS with an average latency of 30-60 ms, H264 endoding and an RJ11 extension port. All for a modest $69 - it almost sounds too good to be true. Well, I got hooked by all the influencer videos and ordered two of them right away. Since one of the two arrived as DOA (defect on arrival), I&amp;rsquo;m only now getting to my conclusion and test.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migration with HCX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/migration-with-hcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/migration-with-hcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was brought in to help with a customer project that involved a VCF setup and migrating the workload domains to a new VCF deployment. The challenge of this project was that we had to adopt the existing networks without making any changes while also reducing the downtime of the workloads to an absolute minimum. We used HCX and network extension to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hcx&#34;&gt;What is HCX?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VMware HCX is an application mobility platform designed to simplify application migration, workload redeployment, and disaster recovery in data centers and clouds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Apply To works in NSX DFW</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-apply-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-apply-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When working with the &lt;strong&gt;NSX Distributed Firewall (DFW)&lt;/strong&gt;, one feature that often goes unnoticed or misunderstood is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;Apply To&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Despite its importance, it is frequently underestimated or even ignored. This is unfortunate, as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;Apply To&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful feature that can significantly influence how firewall rules are applied within an NSX environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many VMware training courses, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;Apply To&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; is either poorly explained or not mentioned at all. As a result, administrators and engineers might miss out on opportunities to optimize their firewall rule configurations. Misunderstanding or neglecting this feature can lead to overly complex rulesets or unexpected behavior in distributed environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More performance trough NSX Edge TEP groups?</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-tep-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-tep-groups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My esteemed colleague, Steven Schramm, recently published an excellent article titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-techtalk.com/posts/multitep-ha/&#34;&gt;Improving NSX Datacenter TEP Performance and Availability - Multi-TEP and TEP Group High Availability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. This inspired me to explore how TEP Groups influence performance in NSX, specifically focusing on how North/South traffic can benefit from their implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-tep-groups-and-why-are-they-interesting&#34;&gt;What Are TEP Groups and Why Are They Interesting?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With NSX 4.2.1, TEP High Availability (HA) for Edge Transport Nodes was introduced. In addition to the HA feature, the load-sharing behavior was also modified.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redeploy an NSX Edge VM Appliance</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-edge-redeploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:00:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-edge-redeploy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are situations where you might need to redeploy an NSX Edge node. This could happen if an Edge VM becomes non-functional, or if it needs to be relocated within the datacenter—for instance, to a different datastore or compute resource. You might also redeploy to move the node to another network. Of course, the specific reasons for redeployment depend on your enviroment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that redeployment applies exclusively to existing NSX Edge nodes and can only be performed with an NSX Edge VM appliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
