<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nfs on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/nfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nfs on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/nfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VCF Import Tool - Run VCF with NFS as pricipal Storage </title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vcf-import-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VCF is a powerful platform designed to simplify the deployment of vSphere, NSX and the Aria product family.&#xA;This is both a blessing and a curse. On the one hand, the Cloudbuilder and SDDC Manager significantly simplify deployment, but this also takes away a certain amount of flexibility.&#xA;In addition, not every customer starts on a greenfield site.&#xA;Another point is the need for resources, which affects us home labbers in particular.&#xA;Many want to prepare for the new VCP exams and are now forced to deploy VCF in their Homelab.&#xA;There are already many solutions for this, such as the Holodeck or the Automated Lab Deployment Scrip from the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lamw/vcf-automated-lab-deployment&#34;&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;, but in my view this is too far removed from the kind of deployment that a customer will experience.&#xA;Therefore I will show several ways how to create VCF as close as possible to a real deployment without needing the real resources.&#xA;In this article I would like to show you how to do a convert with the VCF Import Tool. I will write more articles about VCF deployment in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
