<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unraid on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/unraid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unraid on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:21:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/unraid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>iSCSI Tuning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/iscsi-tuning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:21:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/iscsi-tuning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use iSCSI in combination with Unraid as my DIY block storage solution. To achieve this, I rely on the Linux iSCSI implementation, which I installed on Unraid through a plugin. This setup allows me to leverage Unraid’s flexibility while benefiting from block-level storage for various use cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraid - A Storage Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unraid-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unraid-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-custom-unraid-storage-build---flexibility-simplicity-and-future-proofing&#34;&gt;My Custom Unraid Storage Build - Flexibility, Simplicity, and Future-Proofing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a passionate homelaber, I enjoy not only using technology but also understanding and customizing it to suit my needs. My Unraid storage system is one of my longest-running projects, continuously evolving to meet the demands of my homelab.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After thorough research, I decided to go with Unraid – an operating system renowned for its simplicity, flexibility, and scalability. These key features were the deciding factors for me:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab V4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/labv4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/labv4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ready-for-vcf&#34;&gt;Ready for VCF&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have done a huge redesign of my Homelab.&#xA;To better test VCF scenarios, 3 new Minisforum MS-01 have been added.&#xA;These have a 13th generation i9 and are equipped with fast NVMes for memory tiering.&#xA;They also have 2x10G and 2x2.5G networking on board for various VM workloads.&#xA;Furthermore, I converted my storage from NFS to iSCSI with multipathing, which gets even more performance out of my self-built Unraid.&#xA;I manage about 2 GB/s read / 1.2 GB GB/s write and 78K IOPS (Random 4K with 32Q) in a Windows 11 VM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
