<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HCX on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/hcx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HCX on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:00:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/hcx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ReSTNSX with HCX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/restnsx-with-hcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:00:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/restnsx-with-hcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have already written about my experiences with HCX in the past and as brilliant as the tool is for the migration of different workloads, the rework with the distributed firewall can be painful. Because what HCX can&amp;rsquo;t do is move firewall rules or security objects. Fortunately, there is a solution for this: ReSTNSX.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what exactly is ReSTNSX? ReSTNSX describes itself as follows: The ReSTNSX platform simplifies consumption of VMware&amp;rsquo;s NSX API to increase visibility and reduce the risk of errors. Our mission is to enable administrators to easily configure and operate NSX with a straightforward and intuitive user experience.&#xA;We will see in this post whether it is really that simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migration with HCX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/migration-with-hcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/migration-with-hcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was brought in to help with a customer project that involved a VCF setup and migrating the workload domains to a new VCF deployment. The challenge of this project was that we had to adopt the existing networks without making any changes while also reducing the downtime of the workloads to an absolute minimum. We used HCX and network extension to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hcx&#34;&gt;What is HCX?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VMware HCX is an application mobility platform designed to simplify application migration, workload redeployment, and disaster recovery in data centers and clouds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
