<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ansible VLAN deployment with MikroTik</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vlan-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vlan-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yet-another-ansible-post&#34;&gt;Yet Another Ansible Post&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the year comes to a close, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but reflect on the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made with Ansible in the past few weeks. Looking back, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to be satisfied with. After automating my IPAM system and the startup/shutdown process for my lab, I decided to tackle a long-standing annoyance: deploying VLANs for new lab environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main goal is to have a single file that describes all the required VLANs. This file should also allow me to delete or reuse VLANs as needed. Each VLAN must be deployed across three switches and configured as a tagged VLAN on specific ports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPAM Automation with NetBox, Ansible, and Microsoft Windows DNS Server</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ipam-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:00:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ipam-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Managing IP addresses and DNS records manually can be a daunting task, especially in dynamic IT environments. This blog post demonstrates how to leverage NetBox, Ansible, and Microsoft Windows DNS Server to automate IP Address Management (IPAM) and DNS record updates, making your infrastructure more efficient and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-automate-ipam-and-dns&#34;&gt;Why Automate IPAM and DNS?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consistency: Automation minimizes human errors and ensures uniformity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Efficiency: Automating repetitive tasks saves time and allows teams to focus on strategic activities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scalability: As networks grow, automated solutions adapt more easily than manual processes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-goal&#34;&gt;My goal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get a free IP address is dynamically fetched from a defined subnet in NetBox.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The IP address is immediately assigned to the specified FQDN in NetBox.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A corresponding Host A record is created in your Windows DNS Server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the implementation, ensure the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zero to Automation: How I Used ChatGPT to Create My First Ansible Playbook</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/first-steps-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:36:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/first-steps-ansible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to automate the startup and shutdown of my lab environments—both standard and nested labs. While the idea sounded simple, it quickly turned into an interesting challenge. Having never written an Ansible Playbook before, I turned to ChatGPT for help.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-chatgpt&#34;&gt;Why ChatGPT?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest: starting with Ansible can feel overwhelming, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re new to it. My last experience with something remotely similar was years ago, working with PowerShell scripts or even earlier with .NET 3 (yes, I’m &amp;ldquo;that old&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab V5</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 02:00:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/homelab-v5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-homelab-journey-from-unraid-beginnings-to-version-5&#34;&gt;My Homelab Journey: From Unraid Beginnings to Version 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building and optimizing a homelab has always been a passion of mine. Since its inception, my homelab has gone through several iterations, constantly evolving to meet my goals of achieving maximum performance while minimizing power consumption, noise, and physical space requirements. Here is a snapshot of my journey, culminating in the current Version 5 of my homelab.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginning-unraid-with-custom-hardware&#34;&gt;The Beginning: Unraid with Custom Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My homelab journey began with a custom-built Unraid server featuring an Intel i3 11th Generation processor and 64 GB of RAM. This setup acted as an all-in-one solution for storage, virtualization, and container workloads. I even conducted simple nested vSphere tests on this server during its early days. Today, the server is still in use as a storage and Docker host, although I have replaced the underlying hardware four times to keep up with evolving requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iSCSI Tuning</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/iscsi-tuning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 12:21:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/iscsi-tuning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my setup, I use iSCSI in combination with Unraid to create a DIY block storage solution. Unraid, with its flexibility, serves as the foundation, and I utilize the Linux iSCSI implementation installed via a plugin to enable block-level storage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my setup, I use an Intel NUC of the 13th generation, equipped with two 2.5G network adapters. These provide the necessary connectivity for storage traffic. I configured two VMkernel (VMK) adapters specifically for iSCSI traffic, ensuring redundancy and optimized throughput.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAC Learning is your friend</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/mac-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 19:54:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/mac-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When working with nested ESXi environments, understanding the interplay between MAC Learning, Promiscuous Mode, and Forged Transmits is critical. These settings significantly affect how traffic flows in virtualized networks, especially in scenarios involving virtualized hypervisors or advanced network configurations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MAC Learning: Think of it as a switch-like behavior in your virtual environment. It optimizes network traffic by ensuring that each virtual machine (VM) receives only the packets meant for its MAC address.&#xA;Without MAC learning, when the ESXi VM&amp;rsquo;s vNIC connects to a switch port, it only contains a static MAC address.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-vSphere/8.0/vsphere-networking/GUID-E0246B3D-9FB1-4976-8217-5C085863EA9A.html&#34;&gt;(more Information about MAC learning)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraid - A Storage Journey</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/unraid-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/unraid-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-custom-unraid-storage-build---flexibility-simplicity-and-future-proofing&#34;&gt;My Custom Unraid Storage Build - Flexibility, Simplicity, and Future-Proofing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a passionate homelaber, I enjoy not only using technology but also understanding and customizing it to suit my needs. My Unraid storage system is one of my longest-running projects, continuously evolving to meet the demands of my homelab.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After thorough research, I decided to go with Unraid – an operating system renowned for its simplicity, flexibility, and scalability. These key features were the deciding factors for me:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get most out of your Nuc </title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 11:57:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nuc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-things-first&#34;&gt;First things first&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get a second NIC. The Intel NUC Pro has an IO expansion and supports an additional NIC.&#xA;Unfortunately, these are relatively difficult to get in Germany, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth the effort.&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;aside class=&#34;admonition info&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;div class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; width=&#34;24&#34; height=&#34;24&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34;&#xD;&#xA;      stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; class=&#34;feather feather-info&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;circle cx=&#34;12&#34; cy=&#34;12&#34; r=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&lt;/circle&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;line x1=&#34;12&#34; y1=&#34;16&#34; x2=&#34;12&#34; y2=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;line x1=&#34;12&#34; y1=&#34;8&#34; x2=&#34;12.01&#34; y2=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&#xD;&#xA;   &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Search for&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;div class=&#34;admonition-content&#34;&gt;ASUS NUC LAN and USB Expansion Module (90AR0000-P00010)&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&#xD;&#xA;          &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/NIC_hu6903087498817470336.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;          &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/NIC_hu4204005753805133783.jpg&#34; type=&#34;image/jpeg&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;          &lt;img src=&#34;https://sdn-warrior.org/NIC_hu6903087498817470336.webp&#34;alt=&#34;Image of an IO expansion&#34;  width=&#34;1200&#34;  height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/picture&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;IO expansion&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;          &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;vSphere 8 supports the cards natively and you don&amp;rsquo;t have to install any drivers.&#xA;It also supports jumbo frames, which is relevant for NSX Labs.&#xA;It is recommended to use a 2.5 GB managed switch. I am using a Mikrotik with the wonderful name &lt;code&gt;CRS326-4C +20G+2Q&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab V4</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/labv4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/labv4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ready-for-vcf&#34;&gt;Ready for VCF&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have done a huge redesign of my Homelab.&#xA;To better test VCF scenarios, 3 new Minisforum MS-01 have been added.&#xA;These have a 13th generation i9 and are equipped with fast NVMes for memory tiering.&#xA;They also have 2x10G and 2x2.5G networking on board for various VM workloads.&#xA;Furthermore, I converted my storage from NFS to iSCSI with multipathing, which gets even more performance out of my self-built Unraid.&#xA;I manage about 2 GB/s read / 1.2 GB GB/s write and 78K IOPS (Random 4K with 32Q) in a Windows 11 VM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
