<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nsx on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/nsx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nsx on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/nsx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More performance trough NSX Edge TEP groups?</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-tep-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-tep-groups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My esteemed colleague, Steven Schramm, recently published an excellent article titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sdn-techtalk.com/posts/multitep-ha/#what-is-multi-tep-and-tep-group-ha&#34;&gt;Improving NSX Datacenter TEP Performance and Availability - Multi-TEP and TEP Group High Availability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. This inspired me to explore how TEP Groups influence performance in NSX, specifically focusing on how North/South traffic can benefit from their implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-tep-groups-and-why-are-they-interesting&#34;&gt;What Are TEP Groups and Why Are They Interesting?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With NSX 4.2.1, TEP High Availability (HA) for Edge Transport Nodes was introduced. In addition to the HA feature, the load-sharing behavior was also modified.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redeploy an NSX Edge VM Appliance</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-edge-redeploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:00:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-edge-redeploy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are situations where you might need to redeploy an NSX Edge node. This could happen if an Edge VM becomes non-functional, or if it needs to be relocated within the datacenter—for instance, to a different datastore or compute resource. You might also redeploy to move the node to another network. Of course, the specific reasons for redeployment depend on your enviroment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that redeployment applies exclusively to existing NSX Edge nodes and can only be performed with an NSX Edge VM appliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use QoS in NSX</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-qos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 02:00:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-qos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quality of Service (QoS) is a critical aspect of network performance management, especially in complex environments where NSX is deployed. NSX provides powerful QoS capabilities at both the gateway and segment levels, enabling fine-grained control over traffic prioritization and bandwidth allocation. However, understanding the differences between these two levels of QoS implementation is essential for optimizing network performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll delve into how QoS functions on the gateway versus the segment in NSX, explore their respective use cases, and provide insights into selecting the right approach for your network needs. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re managing inter-tenant traffic or fine-tuning internal traffic flows, mastering these distinctions will empower you to make informed decisions and maximize the efficiency of your NSX deployment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSX 4.2.1.1 Hotfix Update</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx4_2_1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 14:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx4_2_1_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest NSX update delivers a comprehensive set of fixes to enhance stability, performance, and security. Here’s a summary of the resolved issues and their impact:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-enhanced-stability-for-virtual-environments&#34;&gt;1. Enhanced Stability for Virtual Environments&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Loss of IP Bindings after VMotion (Issue 3453866): Addressed the removal of IP bindings and logical ports associated with VMs during vMotion events.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Critical ESXi Errors with UENS (Issue 3456283): Fixed intermittent PSODs caused by control priority filter lookups, ensuring smoother ESXi operations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Portgroup Creation Issue (Issue 3458111): Resolved the creation of additional portgroups during full sync, preventing potential vCenter crashes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Transport Zone Reference Issue (Issue 3454291): Fixed transport zone profile mismatches, restoring vMotion and service functionality.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-improved-network-performance&#34;&gt;2. Improved Network Performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TCP Packet Drops in EDP (Issue 3457047): Resolved issues causing TCP connection drops when using Enhanced Datapath configurations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Packet Reordering with LRO (Issue 3456533): Fixed packet reordering issues when HW Large Receive Offload is enabled, improving TCP throughput.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reduced Traffic Performance with UENS and LRO (Issue 3456289): Addressed performance degradation in VSAN workloads.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-robust-security-and-monitoring&#34;&gt;3. Robust Security and Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;NSX UI Alarm for Metrics Delivery Failure (Issue 3456663): Fixed authentication issues following certificate changes to restore metrics delivery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;IDPS and TLS Prevention (Issue 3458040): Enhanced malicious traffic prevention by resolving decryption issues with IDPS.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;IDPS Events and Certificate Verification (Issue 3458038): Restored the flow of IDPS events to Security Intelligence by fixing Kafka channel errors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-stability-in-upgrades-and-configurations&#34;&gt;4. Stability in Upgrades and Configurations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;NSX Manager Slowness (Issue 3453882): Resolved slowness and instability in NSX Manager post-upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edge Node IP Table Rules (Issue 3452795): Ensured proper application of IP table rules on Edge nodes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;NSX Configuration Realization (Issue 3452794): Fixed issues preventing configuration realization on Transport Nodes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-enhancements-in-distributed-firewall-and-flow-management&#34;&gt;5. Enhancements in Distributed Firewall and Flow Management&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DFW Rules During Upgrade (Issue 3450247): Mitigated periods where DFW rules were disabled during the upgrade process.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flow Exporter Alarms (Issues 3429787, 3456644): Fixed alarms and restored flow export functionality for Security Intelligence.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-overlay-and-connectivity-improvements&#34;&gt;6. Overlay and Connectivity Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overlay Segment Connectivity (Issue 3450019): Addressed connectivity loss in Overlay Segments when Edge TEP groups were enabled.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NSX update resolves critical issues to improve operational reliability, security, and performance in virtual environments. For a seamless experience, upgrading to this release is highly recommended. As always, thorough testing in a staging environment before deployment in production is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSX Integration Fortigate</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-integration-fortigate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 19:49:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-integration-fortigate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nsx-integration-for-fortinet-fortigate-firewalls&#34;&gt;NSX integration for Fortinet Fortigate Firewalls&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern SDN solutions are flexible, fast and effective. The rules of the classic perimeter firewall should be exactly the same. To make life easier, Fortinet has an NSX integration that allows us to write our perimeter rules to dynamic NSX groups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-things-first&#34;&gt;First things first&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fortinet NSX integration works via a so-called external connector. For this purpose, the Fortigate contacts the NSX Manager at regular intervals and updates the previously imported groups.&#xA;This allows us to use dynamic groups that were previously created in NSX using tags, for example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSX Identity Firewall – A Case Study With the Flavour VDI</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-idfw-vdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 08:34:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-idfw-vdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;aside class=&#34;admonition info&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;div class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; width=&#34;24&#34; height=&#34;24&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34;&#xD;&#xA;      stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; class=&#34;feather feather-info&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;circle cx=&#34;12&#34; cy=&#34;12&#34; r=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&lt;/circle&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;line x1=&#34;12&#34; y1=&#34;16&#34; x2=&#34;12&#34; y2=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      &lt;line x1=&#34;12&#34; y1=&#34;8&#34; x2=&#34;12.01&#34; y2=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;/line&gt;&#xD;&#xA;   &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;div class=&#34;admonition-content&#34;&gt;There are of course other ways of using the Identity Firewall. This is the way I have used it with my customers so far. Of course, the whole thing is colored by personal preferences, experiences and customer requirements so take this as an idea for your own implementations.&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/aside&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A customer of mine has the use case that his entire environment must be micro-segmented. Of course, this does not stop at the VDI environment. Since my customer uses non-persistent VDIs (the VMs are deleted after each logoff), no tags can be used for the security groups. After deleting the VM, the tag would also be removed and a new VDI would have no tags and would thus be isolated. This can be solved with automation or with the Identity Firewall (a combination of both solutions is also conceivable and makes sense). In the first step, my customer opted for the Identity Firewall because it allows generic VDIs to be used and authorisations to resources can be conveniently controlled via the customer AD. In addition, each user/user group receives individual firewall rules, which corresponds to the need-to-know principle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSX 4.X Certificate exchange of the NSX Manager</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-cert-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 23:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/nsx-cert-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nsx-4x-certificate-exchange-of-the-nsx-manager&#34;&gt;NSX 4.X Certificate exchange of the NSX Manager&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;certificate-creation&#34;&gt;Certificate creation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all, we need a CSR request. This can be created with OPENSSL. It is important that the key is also exported. You can either create 4 individual certificates (VIP and the three manager nodes) or a SAN certificate with all DNS and IP names of the manager nodes. The easiest way is to carry out the request on a manager node. To do this, I create an openssl config file with VIM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
