<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ansible on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</title>
    <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/ansible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ansible on SDN-Warrior | Daniel Krieger</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Daniel Krieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sdn-warrior.org/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ansible VLAN deployment with MikroTik</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vlan-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/vlan-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yet-another-ansible-post&#34;&gt;Yet Another Ansible Post&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the year comes to a close, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but reflect on the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made with Ansible in the past few weeks. Looking back, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to be satisfied with. After automating my IPAM system and the startup/shutdown process for my lab, I decided to tackle a long-standing annoyance: deploying VLANs for new lab environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main goal is to have a single file that describes all the required VLANs. This file should also allow me to delete or reuse VLANs as needed. Each VLAN must be deployed across three switches and configured as a tagged VLAN on specific ports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPAM Automation with NetBox, Ansible, and Microsoft Windows DNS Server</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ipam-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:00:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/ipam-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Managing IP addresses and DNS records manually can be a daunting task, especially in dynamic IT environments. This blog post demonstrates how to leverage NetBox, Ansible, and Microsoft Windows DNS Server to automate IP Address Management (IPAM) and DNS record updates, making your infrastructure more efficient and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-automate-ipam-and-dns&#34;&gt;Why Automate IPAM and DNS?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consistency: Automation minimizes human errors and ensures uniformity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Efficiency: Automating repetitive tasks saves time and allows teams to focus on strategic activities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scalability: As networks grow, automated solutions adapt more easily than manual processes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-goal&#34;&gt;My goal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get a free IP address is dynamically fetched from a defined subnet in NetBox.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The IP address is immediately assigned to the specified FQDN in NetBox.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A corresponding Host A record is created in your Windows DNS Server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the implementation, ensure the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zero to Automation: How I Used ChatGPT to Create My First Ansible Playbook</title>
      <link>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/first-steps-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:36:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sdn-warrior.org/posts/first-steps-ansible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to automate the startup and shutdown of my lab environments—both standard and nested labs. While the idea sounded simple, it quickly turned into an interesting challenge. Having never written an Ansible Playbook before, I turned to ChatGPT for help.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-chatgpt&#34;&gt;Why ChatGPT?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest: starting with Ansible can feel overwhelming, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re new to it. My last experience with something remotely similar was years ago, working with PowerShell scripts or even earlier with .NET 3 (yes, I’m &amp;ldquo;that old&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
